Deepika C H

Contact Number: 9880253307 Email ID: deepikabhat09@gmail.com

Career Summary:

HR professional with 11 years of experience across HR functions including HR Business Partnering, implementation of multiple modules on SAP SuccessFactor, HR Operations, HR Generalist, Performance Management Process, Appraisal Process, Employee Engagement, Rewards & Recognition activities, Leave & Attendance Management.

Skills:

- HR Business Partnering
- SAP (SuccessFactor) Implementation & Go-Live process of Employee Central, Time Off, Onboarding / Offboarding, Benefits Modules.
- Benefits & Compensation Management
- Onboarding, Offboarding.
- Payroll Coordination
- Compensation Structuring
- Workforce Improvements
- Leave & Attendance Management
- Training & Development
- Version Control of Company Policies
- Performance Management
- Employee Retention
- Statutory Compliance
- Good Telephonic & E-mail Etiquette
- Interpersonal Communication
- Good hands-on experience using Excel (Formulas, pivot, shortcuts), MS Word, PowerPoint.

Work Experience:

One.in Digitech Media Pvt. Ltd., (Part of Greynium Information Technologies – Parent Entity) Assistant Manager – HR

Dec, 2016 - Till Date

HR Business Partnering:

- Work with line managers and employees to improve work relationships, build morale and increase productivity, retention. Address all types of employee issues and grievances.
- Provide day-day performance management guidance to line management (eg: disciplinary actions, pro-active retention measures etc).
- Enhanced team workflows and employee job satisfaction by coordinating communication between managers and employees.
- Identify training needs for teams and individuals and facilitate the same.
- Maintaining Attrition Report across organization.
- Work with the TA team to drive hiring and ensure manpower requirement is met as per the policies.
- Own, drive, advise and support line managers through the annual HR processes around performance, promotions, bonus, annual pay, potential assessment, etc.

SAP SuccessFactors:

- Worked from Implementation to Go-Live of Employee Central, Time Off, Onboarding / Offboarding, Benefits Modules.
- Was responsible for digitization of over 1000 employees' records.
- Was involved in the induction process of SAP SF.
- Responsible for regular data audits to ensure 100% accuracy.

HR Operations:

- Handled end to end Onboarding, New Hire Orientation, Offboarding processes.
- Monitoring the data being uploaded to HR information systems and auditing for accuracy and compliance.
- Ensured documentation of all statutory documents.
- Responsible for Leave & Attendance management of employees across organization.
- Act as a point of contact for employees and provide support for various subjects such as leaves, compensation & benefits, and resolve their queries
- Played a major role in end-to-end transition from in-built HRM tool to FlexiEle software.
- Conducted various sessions on PF Queries, Medical Insurance, Addressing Employee grievance

Employee Engagement:

- Undertaking multiple HR / Change Initiatives to engage and retain the talent. Facilitating the path of job satisfaction and employee morale.
- Part of planning and organizing events across locations and for Work from Home employees.

HR Policies:

- Review and update HR policies to ensure compliance with relevant legislations and that policies are competitive, fair and robust,
- Review and evaluate ways to streamline the HR processes and workflows to stay relevant and improve efficiency.
- Involved in updating the version control of HR policies as and when there are any changes.

Performance Management:

• Lead the implementation of Performance Management strategies that are aligned with organizational strategic thrusts, Lead the annual Performance Management cycle, conducting briefings and developing guidelines as necessary.

Compensation & Benefits:

- Support the team and assist them in the building of compelling compensation offers for candidates, play an active role in the salary planning process.
- Working on maintaining up-to-date minimum wages across organization and providing data for compensation restructure. Also involved in educating employees about the impact of structure change.
- Analyze trends in compensation and benefits plan; and educating employees on the benefits that they
 are eligible for. Working on salary revision during Appraisals.

Reward & Recognition - Talent Development:

• Successfully managed, retained, critical talent through various interventions like internal transfers, skills matrix, performance improvement, speed mentoring, rewards and recognition.

Change Management:

• Successfully managed change management multiple times in extremely complex, dynamic and matrix environment.

Oneindia.com (Greynium Information Technologies Pvt Ltd).

Sr. Recruitment Executive

Aug, 2012 – Dec, 2016

Oneindia.com is an Indian online portal owned by Greynium Information Technologies Pvt. Ltd. The website provides news updates, sports events, travel, entertainment, business, lifestyle, videos, and classifieds in English and 9 regional languages. Oneindia has portals in several Indian languages, including Kannada, Hindi, Tamil, Telugu, Bengali, Gujarati and Malayalam.

- Sourcing, Screening & matching the Profiles based on Job Description.
- End to end Recruitment solutions including personal interviews with candidates to ascertain their competencies, skills and aspirations (positions, salary, relocation aspects Etc.)
- Ensuring all initial screening of resumes & short listing of candidates is done in proper manner.
- Interacting with the teams.
- Analyze the resource requirement for different functions & roles in coordination with the Team leads/Heads.
- Performing activities like Internal Job posting, job posting on social media sites.
- Interview finalization and to keep a track on selected candidates with joining date and updating to the management.
- Salary Negotiation
- Preparing daily report.

Documentation and other activities:

- Maintaining KYC Details, PF Declaration Forms.
- Maintaining employee database containing personal information, bank details, aadhar card details etc.
- Handling employee grievance.
- Educating employees about Company Policies and Employee Welfare policies.
- Keeping records of all new joinees like documentation, filing etc.
- Conducting employee engagement activities.
- Conducting meetings, cultural activities & celebrations.

Wizmatrix Consulting

HR Executive

Oct, 2011 – Mar, 2012

A reputed name in the Industry, Wizmatrix acts as an extended arm of the Hiring Company in enabling solutions for their hiring needs

- Ensuring all initial screening of resumes & short listing of candidates is done in proper manner.
- Sourcing the profiles through portals, networking, employee referrals, walk-ins and existing database.
- Taking initial round of HR interview.
- Coordinating the interviews and also taking care of the events accordingly.
- Getting the approvals for offers and offers the candidates and follows up on the joining.
- Maintaining various MIS like HR Monthly Review, Hiring report, Walk-in report, Headcount report,

PeopleCare HR Solutions

Sr. Recruitment Executive

Feb, 2011 to Sep, 2011

- Ensuring all initial screening of resumes & short listing of candidates is done in proper manner.
- Preparing weekly & Monthly report of hiring.
- Handled Clients and worked for their requirements and served them efficiently.
- Sourcing the profiles through portals, networking, employee referrals, walk-ins and existing database.
- Conducting initial round of HRs interview.

Education:

BSc in Computer Science BMS College for Women

June, 2010

Master of Business Administration (Human Resources)

February, 2015

Sikkim Manipal University.

Diploma in Labour Law & Administrative Law Annamalai University

April, 2008

Strengths:

- Challenging, ability to grasp easily, & flexible.
- Willingness to learn & accept failures to restart again more rigorously.
- Optimistic, Can adapt to situation fast and willing to accept challenges.

Languages:

English, Kannada, Hindi, Tulu.

Personal Details:

Date of Birth: 09 June, 1989

Nationality: Indian Marital Status: Married

Gender: Female

Hobbies: Travelling, Driving, Reading Books, Listening to Music

Address: #498/L, Shivaji Layout, Somanahalli, Kanakapura Main Road, Bangalore – 560 082.

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the information provided above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date:

Place: Bangalore